Guide to the Kirsten Flagstad Collection
Kirsten Flagstad collection,
1923-1962
ARS-2004-01
Flagstad, Kirsten
86 sound tape reels
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection contains recordings of Kirsten Flagstad and Waldemar Alme in performances and interviews.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
Kirsten Flagstad (1895-1962), an operatic soprano, spent the first 18 years of her career in Scandinavia, singing opera, operetta and musical comedy. After performing Isolde in 1932 at the National Theatre, Oslo, she was invited to Bayreuth, where her performances in small Wagnerian roles led to invitations to the Metropolitan Opera in New York, to the San Francisco Opera, and to Covent Garden. She became known for her Wagnerian roles, particularly Sieglinde, Isolde and Brunnhilde. In 1941, Flagstad returned to Norway to join her husband who was later arrested as a Nazi collaborator and died awaiting trial in 1946; she, herself, was acquitted of any wrongdoing. In 1948, Flagstad returned to Covent Garden, performing there, and in other European venues, until 1951. Retiring from the operatic stage in 1953 after a performance of Dido and Aeneas at the Little Mermaid Theatre in London, she continued to give recitals, make recordings, primarily off Wagner and Norwegian composers, and was, for a few years, the director of the Norwegian State Opera.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains recordings of Kirsten Flagstad from the early 1920s until her death in 1962. The recordings are from live radio broadcasts, commercial discs, live performances, recording sessions, and private recordings. It also includes interviews, recordings of Waldemar Alme, piano accompanist to Kirsten Flagstad, and a gift compilation given to Kirsten Flagstad on her deathbed. Conductors, interviewers and other performers on the recordings include Lauritz Melchior, Arnold Gábor, Ludwig Hoffmann, Gertrud Påalson-Wettergren, Emanuel List, Julius Huehn, René Maison, Kathryn Meisle, Set Svanholm, Edwin MacArthur, Alfred Wallenstein, Artur Bodanzky, Oivin Fjelstad, Sigvart Fotland, Maria Müller, Rudolf Bockelmann, Wilhelm Furtwängler, Karen-Marie Flagstad, Karl Böhm, John Gurney, Eleanor Lamont, Knud Hagermann-Lindencrøne, Sir Adrian Boult and Torstein Gunnarson.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962.; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962--Interviews.; Alme, Waldemar.; Operas.; Operas--Excerpts.; Songs (High voice).; Piano music.; Live sound recordings.
Container List
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Act II, parts I & II Jan. 2, 1937, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch 141; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 3701021)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Gábor, Arnold, 1880-1950; Hoffmann, Ludwig, 1895-1963; Melchior, Lauritz; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde Act II, Parts I & II; Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Ho-jo-to-ho!; Tannhäuser. Dich, teure Halle.1938, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 3801291)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Pålson-Wettergren, Gertrud, 1897-; Melchior, Lauritz; List, Emanuel; Huehn, Julius; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcasts, Jan. 29, 1938, Feb. 17, 1940 and Dec. 16, 1939.
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814). SelectionsDec. 31, 1938, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 3812311)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); List, Emanuel; Maison, René, 1895-1962; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast. This tape includes the beginning of the opera to the end of #15 and is continued on 381231 M2.
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814). SelectionsDec. 31, 1938, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 3812312)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); List, Emanuel; Maison, René, 1895-1962; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast. This tape includes from Leonore overture #3 to the end. The first part of the opera is on tape 381231 M1.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre, Scene 4; Tristan und Isolde. Act I, Scene 5Oct. 20, 1939, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 3910201)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; San Francisco Opera; Huehn, Julius; Meisle, Kathryn, 1899-1970; Melchior, Lauritz; Swanholm, Set; McArthur, Edwin. Recording: Walküre recording is taken from a disc of unknown date; Tristan is a recording of a performance at the San Francisco War Memorial Opera House, Oct. 20, 1939.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Acts II-III.Feb. 17, 1940, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 4002171)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Huehn, Julius. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast. Continued on 400217 M2 and 400217 M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Acts II-III, Feb. 17, 1940.1940, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 4002172)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Huehn, Julius. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast. Continues 400217 M1 and continued on 400217 M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Acts II-III.Feb. 17, 1940, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 141; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 4002173)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Huehn, Julius. Recording: Metropolitan Opera radio broadcast. Continues 400217 M1 and 400217 M2.
- Los Angeles Philharmonic concertNov. 16-17, 1950, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., BASF; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 5011161)
  Performers: Performers: Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Wallenstein, Alfred, conductor; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: KFAC Los Angeles broadcast of a concert by the Los Angeles Philharmonic Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 Geschopfe des Prometheus. Ouverture; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827.Symphonies, no. 7, op. 92, A major. Selections.Recording is continued on 501116 M2. Program notes are recorded on 501116 S1.
  KFAC
- Los Angeles Philharmonic concert.Nov. 16-17, 1950, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 5011162)
  Performers: Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Wallenstein, Alfred, conductor; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: KFAC Los Angeles broadcast of a concert by the Los Angeles Philharmonic with Kirsten Flagstad. Recording continues 501116 M1 and is continued by 5011116 M3. Program notes are recorded on 501116 S1. Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ah, perfido!; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Trauermarsch; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang
- Los Angeles Philharmonic concertNov. 16-17, 1950, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 5011163)
  Performers: Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Wallenstein, Alfred; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: KFAC Los Angeles broadcast of a concert by the Los Angeles Philharmonic. Continues tape 501116 M2. Program notes are recorded on 501116 S1. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. 1. Aufzug. Einleitung.
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814)1951, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Full-range FR-7; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 5103101)
  Performers: Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: from disc. Continues on 510310 M2.
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814)1951, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Full-range FR-7; 7 in. (Box 1, Folder 5103102)
  Performers: Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: from disc. Continues 510310 M1.
- Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Songs. Selections; Interview of Kirsten Flagstad by G. Lange, Sept. 27, 19531953, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5309271)
  Performers: Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway). Orkester; Fjeldstad, Øivin, conductor; Lange, G., interviewer; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: The musical contents are duplicated on 530927 M2. Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Nykelen; Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Ballade; Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Skinnvengbrev
- Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Songs. SelectionsSept. 17, 1953, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5309272)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway). Orkester; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Lange, G. Recording: the contents duplicate the musical portions of 530927 M1. Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Nykelen; Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Ballade; Lie, Harald, 1902-1942. Skinnvengbrev
- Norsk Orkesterkonsert i Oslo1953, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch 111 A; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5310151)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; orchestra unknown. Kielland, Olav, 1901-. Mot Blåsnøhøgdom; Irgens Jensen, Ludvig, 1894-1969. Partitasinfonica. To satser; Dørumsgaard, Arne. Sanger under skjernene; Kvandal, Johan. Solo-kantate, no. 1; Svendsen, Johan Severin, 1840-1911. Forspill till Sigurd Slembe.
- Personen og personlighetenDec. 12, 1953, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5312121)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown interviewer. Recording: radio interview
- Beethoven, Ludwig, 1770-1827. Songs. Selections1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5409001)
  Performer: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist. Recording: Recorded live. Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Lieder, op. 48; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Gesänge, op. 83. Wonne der Wehmutge; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Andenken; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Zärtliche Liebe; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. An die Hoffnung, op. 94
- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Songs. Selections1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5409002)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar, piano. Recording: recorded live, May and September, 1954. Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Romanzen aus L. Tiecks Magelone. Selections; Lieder und Gesänge, op. 59. Dein blaues Auge; Lieder, op. 86. Therese; Lieder, op. 46. An die Nachtigall; Lieder und Gesänge, op. 32. Wie bist du, meine Königin.
- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Songs. Selections1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5409003)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar, piano. Recording: recorded live May and September, 1954. Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Gedichte von Scheffel, Mörike, Goethe und Kerner. Zur Ruh, zur Ruh!; Mörike-Lieder. Gebet; Mörike-Lieder. Lebe wohl; Mörike-Lieder. Gesang Weylas; Goethe-Lieder. Anakreons Grab; Italienisches Liederbuch. Heb auf dein blondes Haupt; Gedichte von Robert Reinick. Morgenstimmung
- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Songs. Selections1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5409004)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: recorded live May and September, 1954. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Geduld; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. September; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. Im Abendrot; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 49. Waldseligkeit; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 49. Sie wissen's nicht; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 29. Nachtgang; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 41. Wiegenlied
- Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Songs. SelectionsSept. 25, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5409251)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar, piano. Alme, Waldemar; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Laulut, op. 36. Demanten på marssnön; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Arioso, soprano, string orchestra, op. 3; arr.; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Laulut, op. 37. Första kyssen; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Laulut, op. 37. Flickan kom ifrån sin älsklings möte; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Laulut, op. 37. Var det en dröm?
- Farewell concert, New YorkMar. 20 or 22, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5503201)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Symphony of the Air. Recording: Kirsten Flagstad's second "Farewell" concert and her last public performance. Continued on 550320 M2 and 550320 M3. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Fliegende Holländer. Ouvertüre; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Männer Sippe; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal. Charfreitagszauber; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder
- Farewell concert, New YorkMar. 20 or 22, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5503202)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Symphony of the Air. Recording: Kirsten Flagstad's second "Farewell" concert and her last public performance. Continues 550320 M2 and continued by 550320 M3. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. 1. Aufzug. Einleitung; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Siegfrieds Rheinfahrt
- Farewell concert, New YorkMar. 20 or 22, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5503203)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Symphony of the Air. Recording: Kirsten Flagstad's second "Farewell" concert and her last public performance. Continues 550320 M1 and 550320 M2. The tape concludes with 7 minutes and 15 seconds of applause. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang.
- Norsk romanserMay 31, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5505201)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist. Recording: Live? recording of Kirsten Flagstad singing Norwegian songs (possibly folk songs) accompanied by an unnamed pianist. Det er fjord; Fattig er mitt liv; Preludium; Runde; Kvi tralar det ikkje; Febrüarmorgen; De fyrste songen; Nocturne; Her vil eg kvile; Det är vackrast; Det tredje fottrinn; Hymne til solen.
- Waldemar Alme performing Chopin, Sinding and Friedman1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 2, Folder 5506001)
  Performer: Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Piano recital Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Sonatas, piano, no. 3, op. 58, B minor; Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 27. No. 2; Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Polonaises, piano, op. 53, A? major; Sinding, Christian, 1856-1941. Stücke, piano, op. 32. Frühlingsrauschen; Friedman, Ignaz. Wiener dans.
  Piano music
- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. HaugtussaSept. 16, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5509161)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar, piano. Recording: Recital
- American program1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600001)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Recital. Continued on 560000 M2 Barber, Samuel, 1910- Songs, op. 10. Rain has fallen; Hageman, Richard, 1882-1966. Music I heard with you; Carpenter, John Alden. 1876-1951. Sleep that flits a baby's eye; Watts, Wintter, 1884-1962. With the tide.
- Recital1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600002)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar; Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. White peace; Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. Irish songs (1922). Cradle song; Head, Michael, 1900-1976. Little road to Bethlehem; Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Lieder aus dem Norwegischen (1890). Verborg'ne Liebe; Bridge, Frank, 1879-1941. Love went a-riding
- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Songs. Selections1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600003)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Recital Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Junge Nonne; Winterreise. Post; Ellens Gesang, D. 839; Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Liebesbotschaft; Erlkönig
- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Songs. Selections1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600004)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Recital Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Myrthen. Aus den östlichen Rosen; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Myrthen. Zum Schluss; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Lieder und Gesänge, op. 27. Jasminenstrauch; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Gedichte aus "Liebesfrühling." Himmel hat eine Träne geweint; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Lieder und Gesänge, op. 51. Liebeslied
- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Songs. Selections1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600005)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Recital Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lyriske stykker, op. 71. Efterklang; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Liden højt deroppe; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Digte af Otto Benzon, op. 70. Lys nat; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Et håb; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Digte, op. 25. Borte; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Digte af Otto Benzon, op. 69. Gynger en båd på bølge; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Digte af Vilhelm Krag. Og jeg vil ha mig en hjertenskjaer
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600006)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continued on 560000 M7, 560000 M8, 560000 M9, 560000 M10 and 560000 M11. Alltid Freidig hvor du går; Lover den Herre; Av höyheten opprimmen er; Den signede dag; Gud signe vårt dyre fedreland; Fred til bot for bittert savn; Gard skal allting lage; Herre Gud, ditt dyre navn; Dype, stille, sterke, milde; Hvo ene lader Herren råde
  Hymns, Norwegian; Songs (High voice) with organ
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600007)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continues 560000 M6 and continued by 560000 M8, 560000 M9, 560000 M10 and 560000 M11. Inger vinner frem til den evige ro; I prektige himler; Jeg ser deg o Gud's lam; Kjaerlidhet er lysets kilde; Lied milde, Ljos; Jesus din söte forening; Velt alle dine veit
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600008)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continues 560000 M6 and 560000 M7 and continued by 560000 M9, 560000 M10 and 560000 M11. Eg lyfter opp til Gud min song; Overmåde fullt av nåde; På Gude alene; Sörg, o kjaere Fader du; Sions vekter hever rösten; Kjaerlighet fra Gud; Vår Gud han er så fast en borg; Alene Gud i Himmerik.
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 5600009)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continues 560000 M6, 560000 M7, 560000 M8 and continued by 560000 M10 and 560000 M11. Da Herre som er sterk; Hellig, hellig, hellig; Når mitt öye brett av möye; Min sjel, min sjel lov Herre; Fagert er landet; Påskemorgen slukker sorgen; Kjaerlighet fra Gud II (Thompson); I Jesu navn skal all vår gjerning skue; Eg veit i Himmerik ei borg.
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 56000010)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continues 560000 M6, 560000 M7, 560000 M8, 560000 M9 and continued by 560000 M11. Fotland, Sigvart; Et er nödig; Jesus dine sype vinder; Mitt hjerte alltid vanker; Hvor selig er den lille flokk; Nu la oss takke Gud Den store, hvite flokk; Kirken den er et gammelt hus; Deilig er Jorden.
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 56000011)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Fotland, Sigvart, organ. Recording: Riis Church, Norway. Continues 560000 M6, 560000 M7, 560000 M8, 560000 M9 and 560000 M10. Jesus det eneste; Jesus når eg må få fylgja med deg; Kvardagskristen vil eg væra; I denae verdens sorgen senkt.
- Norwegian hymns1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 56000012)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Fjeldstad, Øivin, conductor. Av höyheten opprimmen er; Den store hvite flokk; Deilig er Jorden; Lover den Herre; Velt alle dine veit; Vaar Gud han er saa fast en borg; Kjaerlighet er lyset kilde; Ingen vinner frem til den evige ro; Kirken den er et gammelt hus.
  Hymns, Norwegian; Songs (High voice) with orchestra
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act III1937, 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 3, Folder 56000013)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Müller, Maria; Bockelmann, Rudolf; London Philharmonic Orchestra; Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954. Recording: Live performance at Covent Garden, London, May, 1937. Re-recorded from disc in 1956.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Act 1, Part 1Jan. 5, 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601051)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English. Continued by 560105 M2--M4, 560108 M1--M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 1, Part 21956560105 M1, 560105 M3, 560105 M4, 560108, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601052)